[
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mi Magyarország államformája?",
        "answer":  "Köztársaság",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is Hungary\u0027s form of government?",
                                        "answer":  "Republic"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая форма правления в Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Республика"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Mi Magyarország államformája?",
        "correctCount":  1,
        "options":  [
                        "Köztársaság",
                        "Monarchia",
                        "Diktatúra"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is Hungary\u0027s form of government?",
                                        "answer":  "Republic"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая форма правления в Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Республика"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mekkora km² Magyarország területe?",
        "answer":  "93 ezer ÷ 93000",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is the area of Hungary?",
                                        "answer":  "93 thousand km² ÷ 93000 km²"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какова площадь Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "93 тысячи км² ÷ 93000 км²"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány millió fő Magyarország népessége?",
        "answer":  "9,6 millió fő ÷ 9,6 millió ÷ 9.6 millió",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many million people live in Hungary?",
                                        "answer":  "9.6 million people"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько миллионов человек проживает в Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "9,6 миллиона человек"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mi Magyarország fővárosa?",
        "answer":  "Budapest",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is the capital of Hungary?",
                                        "answer":  "Budapest"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая столица Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Будапешт"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mi Magyarország pénzneme?",
        "answer":  "Forint",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is Hungary\u0027s currency?",
                                        "answer":  "Forint"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая валюта Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Форинт"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mi Magyarország hivatalos nyelve?",
        "answer":  "Magyar",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is Hungary\u0027s official language?",
                                        "answer":  "Hungarian"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какой официальный язык Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Венгерский"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel három magyarországi tájegységet",
        "answer":  "Alföld ÷ Alpokalja ÷ Dunántúli-dombság ÷ Dunántúli-középhegység ÷ Északi-középhegység ÷ Kisalföld",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List three Hungarian landscapes!",
                                        "answer":  "Great Hungarian Plain ÷ Alpokalja ÷ Transdanubian Hills ÷ Transdanubian Central Range ÷ Northern Central Range ÷ Little Hungarian Plain"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите три венгерские природные зоны!",
                                        "answer":  "Великая Венгерская равнина ÷ Альпокалья ÷ Трансдунбийские холмы ÷ Трансдунбийское среднегорье ÷ Северное среднегорье ÷ Малая Венгерская низменность"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik Magyarország tájegysége?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Alföld",
                        "Dunántúli-középhegység",
                        "Északi-középhegység",
                        "Alpok",
                        "Kárpátok"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a Hungarian landscape?",
                                        "answer":  "Great Hungarian Plain, Transdanubian Central Range, Northern Central Range"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является венгерской природной зоной?",
                                        "answer":  "Великая Венгерская равнина, Среднегорье Трансдунубии, Северное среднегорье"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány tájegysége van Magyarországnak?",
        "answer":  "6 ÷ Hat",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many landscapes does Hungary have?",
                                        "answer":  "Six ÷ 6"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько природных зон в Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Шесть ÷ 6"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Sorolja fel Magyarország három legnagyobb tavát",
        "answer":  "Balaton ÷ Fertő tó ÷ Velencei-tó",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List Hungary\u0027s three largest lakes!",
                                        "answer":  "Lake Balaton ÷ Lake Fertő ÷ Lake Velence"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите три крупнейших озера Венгрии!",
                                        "answer":  "Балатон ÷ озеро Фертё ÷ озеро Веленце"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mi Magyarország legnagyobb tava?",
        "answer":  "Balaton",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is Hungary\u0027s largest lake?",
                                        "answer":  "Lake Balaton"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какое крупнейшее озеро Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Балатон"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Sorolja fel Magyarország négy legnagyobb folyóját",
        "answer":  "Duna ÷ Tisza ÷ Dráva ÷ Rába",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List Hungary\u0027s four largest rivers!",
                                        "answer":  "Danube ÷ Tisza ÷ Drava ÷ Rába"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите четыре крупнейшие реки Венгрии!",
                                        "answer":  "Дунай ÷ Тиса ÷ Драва ÷ Раба"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik Magyarország folyója?",
        "correctCount":  4,
        "options":  [
                        "Duna",
                        "Tisza",
                        "Dráva",
                        "Rába",
                        "Viszla",
                        "Oder"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2,
                               3
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a river in Hungary?",
                                        "answer":  "Danube, Tisza, Drava, Rába"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является рекой Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Дунай, Тиса, Драва, Раба"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel öt szomszédos országot",
        "answer":  "Szlovákia ÷ Ukrajna ÷ Románia ÷ Szerbia ÷ Horvátország ÷ Szlovénia ÷ Ausztria",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List five neighboring countries!",
                                        "answer":  "Slovakia ÷ Ukraine ÷ Romania ÷ Serbia ÷ Croatia ÷ Slovenia ÷ Austria"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите пять соседних стран!",
                                        "answer":  "Словакия ÷ Украина ÷ Румыния ÷ Сербия ÷ Хорватия ÷ Словения ÷ Австрия"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány szomszédos országa van Magyarországnak?",
        "answer":  "7 ÷ Hét",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many neighboring countries does Hungary have?",
                                        "answer":  "Seven ÷ 7"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько соседних стран у Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Семь ÷ 7"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik Magyarország szomszédja?",
        "correctCount":  4,
        "options":  [
                        "Szlovákia",
                        "Románia",
                        "Szerbia",
                        "Ausztria",
                        "Lengyelország",
                        "Olaszország",
                        "Németország"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2,
                               3
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a neighbor of Hungary?",
                                        "answer":  "Slovakia, Romania, Serbia, Austria"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является соседом Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Словакия, Румыния, Сербия, Австрия"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel öt Magyarországon élő nemzetiséget!",
        "answer":  "Bolgár ÷ görög ÷ horvát ÷ lengyel ÷ német ÷ örmény ÷ roma ÷ román ÷ ruszin ÷ szerb ÷ szlovák ÷ szlovén ÷ ukrán",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List five nationalities living in Hungary!",
                                        "answer":  "Bulgarian ÷ Greek ÷ Croatian ÷ Polish ÷ German ÷ Armenian ÷ Roma ÷ Romanian ÷ Rusyn ÷ Serbian ÷ Slovak ÷ Slovenian ÷ Ukrainian"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите пять национальностей, проживающих в Венгрии!",
                                        "answer":  "Болгарская ÷ Греческая ÷ Хорватская ÷ Польская ÷ Немецкая ÷ Армянская ÷ Цыганская ÷ Румынская ÷ Русинская ÷ Сербская ÷ Словацкая ÷ Словенская ÷ Украинская"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik nemzetiség él Magyarországon?",
        "correctCount":  5,
        "options":  [
                        "Roma",
                        "Német",
                        "Horvát",
                        "Szerb",
                        "Szlovák",
                        "Francia",
                        "Olasz",
                        "Spanyol"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2,
                               3,
                               4
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is an EU member state?",
                                        "answer":  "Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Poland"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является государством-членом ЕС?",
                                        "answer":  "Германия, Франция, Италия, Испания, Польша"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik NEM EU-tagállam?",
        "correctCount":  1,
        "options":  [
                        "Svájc",
                        "Németország",
                        "Franciaország",
                        "Olaszország"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is NOT an EU member state?",
                                        "answer":  "Switzerland"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая НЕ является государством-членом ЕС?",
                                        "answer":  "Швейцария"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik ország tagja az EU-nak?",
        "correctCount":  4,
        "options":  [
                        "Ausztria",
                        "Belgium",
                        "Hollandia",
                        "Dánia",
                        "Norvégia",
                        "Svájc"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2,
                               3
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which country is a member of the EU?",
                                        "answer":  "Austria, Belgium, Netherlands, Denmark"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая страна является членом ЕС?",
                                        "answer":  "Австрия, Бельгия, Нидерланды, Дания"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány vármegyéje van Magyarországnak?",
        "answer":  "19 ÷ Tizenkilenc",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many counties does Hungary have?",
                                        "answer":  "Nineteen ÷ 19"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько областей в Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Девятнадцать ÷ 19"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel öt vármegyét!",
        "answer":  "Baranya ÷ Borsod-Abaúj-Zemplén ÷ Bács-Kiskun ÷ Békés ÷ Csongrád-Csanád ÷ Fejér ÷ Győr-Moson-Sopron ÷ Hajdú-Bihar ÷ Heves ÷ Jász-Nagykun-Szolnok ÷ Komárom-Esztergom ÷ Nógrád ÷ Pest ÷ Somogy ÷ Szabolcs-Szatmár-Bereg ÷ Tolna ÷ Vas ÷ Veszprém ÷ Zala",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List five counties!",
                                        "answer":  "Baranya ÷ Borsod-Abaúj-Zemplén ÷ Bács-Kiskun ÷ Békés ÷ Csongrád-Csanád ÷ Fejér ÷ Győr-Moson-Sopron ÷ Hajdú-Bihar ÷ Heves ÷ Jász-Nagykun-Szolnok ÷ Komárom-Esztergom ÷ Nógrád ÷ Pest ÷ Somogy ÷ Szabolcs-Szatmár-Bereg ÷ Tolna ÷ Vas ÷ Veszprém ÷ Zala"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите пять областей!",
                                        "answer":  "Барань ÷ Боршод-Абауй-Земплен ÷ Бачки-Кишкун ÷ Бекеш ÷ Чонград-Чанад ÷ Фейер ÷ Дьёр-Мошон-Шопрон ÷ Хайду-Бихар ÷ Хевеш ÷ Яс-Надькун-Шольнок ÷ Комаром-Эстергом ÷ Ноград ÷ Пешт ÷ Шомодь ÷ Саболь-Сатмар-Берег ÷ Толна ÷ Ваш ÷ Веспрем ÷ Зала"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik Magyarország vármegyéje?",
        "correctCount":  5,
        "options":  [
                        "Pest",
                        "Baranya",
                        "Hajdú-Bihar",
                        "Somogy",
                        "Tolna",
                        "Erdély",
                        "Felvidék",
                        "Délvidék"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2,
                               3,
                               4
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a county in Hungary?",
                                        "answer":  "Pest, Baranya, Hajdú-Bihar, Somogy, Tolna"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является областью Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Пешт, Барань, Хайду-Бихар, Шомодь, Толна"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mikor jött létre Budapest?",
        "answer":  "1873.11.17 ÷ 1873 ÷ 1873.11.17",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "When was Budapest created?",
                                        "answer":  "1873.11.17"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Когда был создан Будапешт?",
                                        "answer":  "1873.11.17"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mely városok egyesüléséből jött létre Budapest?",
        "answer":  "Pest ÷ Buda ÷ Óbuda",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "From the merger of which cities was Budapest created?",
                                        "answer":  "From the merger of Pest, Buda and Óbuda"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Из объединения каких городов был создан Будапешт?",
                                        "answer":  "Из объединения Пешта, Буды и Обуды"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Mely városok egyesültek 1873-ban?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Pest",
                        "Buda",
                        "Óbuda",
                        "Kőbánya",
                        "Lipótváros"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which cities united in 1873?",
                                        "answer":  "Pest, Buda, Óbuda"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какие города объединились в 1873 году?",
                                        "answer":  "Пешт, Буда, Обуда"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik folyó választja el Pestet és Budát?",
        "correctCount":  1,
        "options":  [
                        "Duna",
                        "Tisza",
                        "Dráva"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which river separates Pest and Buda?",
                                        "answer":  "Danube"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая река разделяет Пешт и Буду?",
                                        "answer":  "Дунай"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány kerülete van Budapestnek?",
        "answer":  "23 ÷ huszonhárom",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many districts does Budapest have?",
                                        "answer":  "23 ÷ twenty-three"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько районов в Будапеште?",
                                        "answer":  "23 ÷ двадцать три"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mióta van Budapestnek 23 kerülete?",
        "answer":  "1994 óta",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Since when has Budapest had 23 districts?",
                                        "answer":  "1994"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "С каких пор у Будапешта 23 района?",
                                        "answer":  "1994"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel öt budapesti nevezetességet!",
        "answer":  "Budavári Palota ÷ Citadella ÷ Gellért Gyógyfürdő ÷ Halászbástya ÷ Hősök tere ÷ Magyar Nemzeti Múzeum ÷ Magyar Zene Háza ÷ Magyar Állami Operaház ÷ Mátyás-templom ÷ Parlament ÷ Szent István Bazilika ÷ Széchenyi Lánchíd ÷ Szépművészeti Múzeum ÷ Vajdahunyad vára",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List five Budapest landmarks!",
                                        "answer":  "Buda Castle ÷ Citadel ÷ Gellért Spa ÷ Fisherman\u0027s Bastion ÷ Heroes\u0027 Square ÷ Hungarian National Museum ÷ House of Hungarian Music ÷ Hungarian State Opera House ÷ Matthias Church ÷ Parliament ÷ St. Stephen\u0027s Basilica ÷ Széchenyi Chain Bridge ÷ Museum of Fine Arts ÷ Vajdahunyad Castle"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите пять достопримечательностей Будапешта!",
                                        "answer":  "Будайский замок ÷ Цитадель ÷ Купальня Геллерт ÷ Рыбацкий бастион ÷ Площадь Героев ÷ Венгерский национальный музей ÷ Дом венгерской музыки ÷ Венгерский государственный оперный театр ÷ Церковь Матяша ÷ Парламент ÷ Базилика Святого Иштвана ÷ Цепной мост Сечени ÷ Музей изобразительных искусств ÷ Замок Вайдахуняд"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik Budapesti nevezetesség?",
        "correctCount":  5,
        "options":  [
                        "Parlament",
                        "Budavári Palota",
                        "Halászbástya",
                        "Szent István Bazilika",
                        "Turul",
                        "Esztergomi Bazilika",
                        "Akropolisz"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2,
                               3,
                               4
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a landmark in Budapest?",
                                        "answer":  "Parliament, Buda Castle, Fisherman\u0027s Bastion, St. Stephen\u0027s Basilica, Opera House"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является достопримечательностью Будапешта?",
                                        "answer":  "Парламент, Будайский замок, Рыбацкий бастион, Базилика Святого Иштвана, Оперный театр"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel három hungarikum ételt!",
        "answer":  "Gulyásleves ÷ halászlé ÷ dobostorta ÷ Pick téliszalámi",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List three hungarikum foods!",
                                        "answer":  "Goulash soup ÷ Fisherman soup ÷ Dobos cake ÷ Pick winter salami"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите три хунгарикум блюда!",
                                        "answer":  "Гуляш ÷ Байская и Тисайская рыбная уха ÷ Торт Добош ÷ Зимняя салями Пик"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik hungarikum étel?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Gulyásleves",
                        "Halászlé",
                        "Dobostorta",
                        "Paprikás csirke",
                        "Bécsi szelet"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a Hungarian food?",
                                        "answer":  "Goulash soup, Fisherman\u0027s soup, Dobos cake"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является венгерской едой?",
                                        "answer":  "Гуляш, Рыбацкая уха, Торт Добош"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel két hungarikum alapanyagot",
        "answer":  "Makói hagyma ÷ paprika",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List two hungarikum ingredients!",
                                        "answer":  "Makó onion ÷ Kalocsa and Szeged ground paprika"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите два хунгарикум ингредиента!",
                                        "answer":  "Макойский лук ÷ Калочский и Сегедский молотый перец"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik város híres a fűszerpaprikájáról?",
        "correctCount":  2,
        "options":  [
                        "Kalocsa",
                        "Szeged",
                        "Budapest",
                        "Debrecen"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which city is famous for its paprika?",
                                        "answer":  "Kalocsa, Szeged"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какой город знаменит своим перцем?",
                                        "answer":  "Калоч, Сегед"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel két hungarikum italt",
        "answer":  "tokaji aszú ÷ egri bikavér ÷ pálinká",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List two hungarikum drinks!",
                                        "answer":  "Hungarian wines (Tokaji Aszú, Egri Bikavér) ÷ pálinka"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите два хунгарикум напитка!",
                                        "answer":  "Венгерские вина (Токайское асу, Эгри бикавер) ÷ палинка"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik hungarikum ital?",
        "correctCount":  2,
        "options":  [
                        "Tokaji aszú",
                        "Pálinka",
                        "Unicum",
                        "Olaszrizling"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a Hungarian drink?",
                                        "answer":  "Tokaji Aszú, Pálinka"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какой является венгерским напитком?",
                                        "answer":  "Токайское асу, Палинка"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik magyar bor hungarikum?",
        "correctCount":  2,
        "options":  [
                        "Tokaji aszú",
                        "Egri bikavér",
                        "Bordeaux",
                        "Chianti"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which Hungarian wine is a cultural heritage?",
                                        "answer":  "Tokaji Aszú, Egri Bikavér"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какое венгерское вино является культурным наследием?",
                                        "answer":  "Токайское асу, Эгри бикавер"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel két kulturális örökség hungarikumot!",
        "answer":  "Mohácsi busójárás ÷ Pannonhalmi Bencés Főapátság ÷ Hollókő ÷ Füredi Anna-bál ÷ Busójárás",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List two cultural heritage hungarikums!",
                                        "answer":  "Mohács Busó Festival ÷ Pannonhalma Benedictine Abbey ÷ Hollókő ÷ Füred Anna Ball"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите два культурных наследия хунгарикума!",
                                        "answer":  "Мохачский карнавал бусо ÷ Паннонхалмское бенедиктинское аббатство ÷ Холлокё ÷ Бал Анны в Фюреде"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik hungarikum kulturális örökség?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Mohácsi busójárás",
                        "Pannonhalmi Bencés Főapátság",
                        "Hollókő",
                        "Budavári Palotanegyed",
                        "Visegrádi Fellegvár"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a Hungarian cultural heritage?",
                                        "answer":  "Mohács Busó Festival, Pannonhalma Archabbey, Hollókő"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является венгерским культурным наследием?",
                                        "answer":  "Мохачский карнавал бусо, Паннонхалмское аббатство, Холлокё"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel három hungarikum állatot",
        "answer":  "Szürke szarvasmarha ÷ puli ÷ komondor ÷ kuvasz ÷ magyar vizsla ÷ erdélyi kopó",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List three hungarikum animals!",
                                        "answer":  "Gray cattle ÷ Hungarian shepherd dogs (Puli, Komondor, Kuvasz) ÷ Hungarian hunting dogs (Hungarian Vizsla, Transylvanian Hound)"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите три хунгарикум животных!",
                                        "answer":  "Серая корова ÷ Венгерские пастушьи собаки (Пули, Комондор, Кувас) ÷ Венгерские охотничьи собаки (Венгерская выжла, Трансильванская гончая)"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik hungarikum állat?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Szürke szarvasmarha",
                        "Puli",
                        "Magyar vizsla",
                        "Német juhász",
                        "Labrador"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a Hungarian animal?",
                                        "answer":  "Gray cattle, Puli, Hungarian Vizsla"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какое является венгерским животным?",
                                        "answer":  "Серая корова, Пули, Венгерская выжла"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel két magyar pásztorkutyát!",
        "answer":  "Puli ÷ komondor ÷ kuvasz",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List two Hungarian shepherd dogs!",
                                        "answer":  "Puli ÷ Komondor ÷ Kuvasz"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите две венгерские пастушьи собаки!",
                                        "answer":  "Пули ÷ Комондор ÷ Кувас"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik magyar pásztorkutya?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Puli",
                        "Komondor",
                        "Kuvasz",
                        "Collie",
                        "Szürke szarvasmarha"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a Hungarian shepherd dog?",
                                        "answer":  "Puli, Komondor, Kuvasz"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является венгерской пастушьей собакой?",
                                        "answer":  "Пули, Комондор, Кувас"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel két magyar vadászkutyát",
        "answer":  "Magyar vizsla ÷ erdélyi kopó",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List two Hungarian hunting dogs!",
                                        "answer":  "Hungarian Vizsla ÷ Transylvanian Hound"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите две венгерские охотничьи собаки!",
                                        "answer":  "Венгерская выжла ÷ Трансильванская гончая"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel három nép- és iparművészeti hungarikumot",
        "answer":  "Halasi csipke ÷ matyó népművészet ÷ hollóházi és Zsolnay-porcelán",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List three folk and industrial art hungarikums!",
                                        "answer":  "Halas lace ÷ Matyó folk art ÷ Hollóház and Zsolnay porcelain"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите три народных и промышленных искусства хунгарикума!",
                                        "answer":  "Халашское кружево ÷ Матьёское народное искусство ÷ Холлохазский и Золнайский фарфор"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik hungarikum nép- és iparművészet?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Halasi csipke",
                        "Matyó népművészet",
                        "Zsolnay-porcelán",
                        "Korondi fazekasság",
                        "Székelykapu"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a Hungarian folk art?",
                                        "answer":  "Halas lace, Matyó folk art, Zsolnay porcelain"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какое является венгерским народным и прикладным искусством?",
                                        "answer":  "Халашское кружево, Матьёское народное искусство, Порцелан Золнай"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik porcelán hungarikum?",
        "correctCount":  2,
        "options":  [
                        "Hollóházi porcelán",
                        "Zsolnay-porcelán",
                        "Meisseni porcelán",
                        "Limoges-i porcelán"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which porcelain is a Hungarian cultural heritage?",
                                        "answer":  "Hollóház porcelain, Zsolnay porcelain"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какой фарфор является венгерским культурным наследием?",
                                        "answer":  "Порцелан Холлохаз, Порцелан Золнай"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Sorolja fel Magyarország három legrégibb és legjelentősebb felekezetét",
        "answer":  "Katolikus ÷ Református ÷ Evangélikus",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List Hungary\u0027s three oldest and most significant denominations!",
                                        "answer":  "Hungarian Catholic Church ÷ Hungarian Reformed Church ÷ Hungarian Evangelical Church"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите три старейшие и наиболее значимые конфессии Венгрии!",
                                        "answer":  "Венгерская католическая церковь ÷ Венгерская реформатская церковь ÷ Венгерская евангелическая церковь"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik Magyarország jelentős felekezete?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Katolikus",
                        "Református",
                        "Evangélikus",
                        "Anglikán",
                        "Buddhizmus"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is a significant denomination in Hungary?",
                                        "answer":  "Hungarian Catholic Church, Hungarian Reformed Church, Hungarian Evangelical Church"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является значительной конфессией в Венгрии?",
                                        "answer":  "Венгерская католическая церковь, Венгерская реформатская церковь, Венгерская евангелическая церковь"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mikor van karácsony?",
        "answer":  "12.24-12.26 ÷ December 24-26.",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "When is Christmas?",
                                        "answer":  "December 24-26"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Когда Рождество?",
                                        "answer":  "24-26 декабря"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mit ünneplünk karácsonykor?",
        "answer":  "Jézus születését",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What do we celebrate at Christmas?",
                                        "answer":  "Jesus, the birth of the Savior"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Что мы празднуем на Рождество?",
                                        "answer":  "Иисуса, рождение Спасителя"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Kit ünneplünk karácsonykor?",
        "correctCount":  1,
        "options":  [
                        "Jézus születését",
                        "Jézus feltámadását",
                        "Szent István születését"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Who is celebrated at Christmas?",
                                        "answer":  "Jesus\u0027 birth"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Кого празднуют на Рождество?",
                                        "answer":  "Рождение Иисуса"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Mit ünneplünk húsvétkor?",
        "correctCount":  2,
        "options":  [
                        "Jézus kereszthalálára emlékezünk",
                        "Jézus feltámadását ünnepeljük",
                        "Jézus születését",
                        "Szent István születését"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is celebrated at Easter?",
                                        "answer":  "We remember Jesus\u0027 crucifixion, We celebrate Jesus\u0027 resurrection"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Что празднуют на Пасху?",
                                        "answer":  "Мы помним распятие Иисуса, Мы празднуем воскресение Иисуса"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Kire emlékezünk augusztus 20-án?",
        "answer":  "Szent István királyra",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Who do we remember on August 20?",
                                        "answer":  "King Saint Stephen"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "О ком мы помним 20 августа?",
                                        "answer":  "Короля Святого Иштвана"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "person"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Minek a napja augusztus 20.?",
        "answer":  "A magyar államalapítás ÷ Szent István",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What day is August 20?",
                                        "answer":  "Day of Hungarian state foundation ÷ King Saint Stephen\u0027s day"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какой день 20 августа?",
                                        "answer":  "День основания венгерского государства ÷ День короля Святого Иштвана"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Mit tartanak Szent István napján?",
        "correctCount":  2,
        "options":  [
                        "Szent Jobb Körmenet",
                        "Tűzijáték",
                        "Karácsonyi ünnepség",
                        "Húsvéti szertartás"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is held on St. Stephen\u0027s Day?",
                                        "answer":  "Holy Right Procession, Fireworks"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Что проводят в день Святого Иштвана?",
                                        "answer":  "Процессия со Святой Десницей, Фейерверк"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel öt magyar szentet vagy boldogot",
        "answer":  "Szent István ÷ Szent László ÷ Szent Imre ÷ Szent Gellért ÷ Szent Margit ÷ Szent Erzsébet",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List five Hungarian saints or blessed!",
                                        "answer":  "Saint Stephen ÷ Saint Ladislaus ÷ Saint Emeric ÷ Saint Gerard ÷ Saint Margaret of Árpád House ÷ Saint Elizabeth of Árpád House"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите пять венгерских святых или блаженных!",
                                        "answer":  "Святой Иштван ÷ Святой Ласло ÷ Святой Имре ÷ Святой Геллерт ÷ Святая Маргит из дома Арпадов ÷ Святая Эржебет из дома Арпадов"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Ki magyar szent?",
        "correctCount":  4,
        "options":  [
                        "Szent István",
                        "Szent László",
                        "Szent Imre",
                        "Szent Gellért",
                        "Szent Péter",
                        "Szent Pál"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2,
                               3
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Who is a Hungarian saint?",
                                        "answer":  "Saint Stephen, Saint Ladislaus, Saint Emeric, Saint Gerard"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Кто является венгерским святым?",
                                        "answer":  "Святой Иштван, Святой Ласло, Святой Имре, Святой Геллерт"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mikor csatlakozott Magyarország az Európai Unióhoz?",
        "answer":  "2004.05.01 ÷ 2004.05.01",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "When did Hungary join the European Union?",
                                        "answer":  "2004.05.01"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Когда Венгрия присоединилась к Европейскому Союзу?",
                                        "answer":  "2004.05.01"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány millió polgár él az Európai Unióban?",
        "answer":  "450 millió ÷ 450",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many million citizens live in the European Union?",
                                        "answer":  "450 million"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько миллионов граждан проживает в Европейском Союзе?",
                                        "answer":  "450 миллионов"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mikor csatlakozott Magyarország a schengeni övezethez?",
        "answer":  "2007 ÷ 2007",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "When did Hungary join the Schengen area?",
                                        "answer":  "2007"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Когда Венгрия присоединилась к Шенгенской зоне?",
                                        "answer":  "2007"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Mit jelent a schengeni övezet?",
        "correctCount":  1,
        "options":  [
                        "A határok szabad átjárhatóságát",
                        "Közös pénznemet",
                        "Közös hadsereget"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What does the Schengen area mean?",
                                        "answer":  "Free movement of borders"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Что означает Шенгенская зона?",
                                        "answer":  "Свободное пересечение границ"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Mi az Európai Unió központja?",
        "answer":  "Brüsszel",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "What is the headquarters of the European Union?",
                                        "answer":  "Brussels"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Где находится штаб-квартира Европейского Союза?",
                                        "answer":  "Брюссель"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel három EU intézményt",
        "answer":  "Európai Bizottság ÷ Tanács ÷ Európai Parlament ÷ Európai Tanács",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List three EU institutions!",
                                        "answer":  "European Commission ÷ Council ÷ European Parliament ÷ European Council"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите три института ЕС!",
                                        "answer":  "Европейская комиссия ÷ Совет ÷ Европейский парламент ÷ Европейский совет"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Multiple",
        "question":  "Melyik az EU intézménye?",
        "correctCount":  3,
        "options":  [
                        "Európai Bizottság",
                        "Európai Parlament",
                        "Európai Tanács",
                        "ENSZ",
                        "NATO"
                    ],
        "correctIndices":  [
                               0,
                               1,
                               2
                           ],
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "Which one is an EU institution?",
                                        "answer":  "European Commission, European Parliament, European Council"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Какая является институтом ЕС?",
                                        "answer":  "Европейская комиссия, Европейский парламент, Европейский совет"
                                    }
                         }
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Milyen gyakran tartanak európai parlamenti választásokat?",
        "answer":  "5 év ÷ 5 ÷ Ötévente",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How often are European Parliament elections held?",
                                        "answer":  "Every five years"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Как часто проводятся выборы в Европейский парламент?",
                                        "answer":  "Каждые пять лет"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány fővel képviselteti magát Magyarország az Európai Parlamentben?",
        "answer":  "21 fővel ÷ 21",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many representatives does Hungary have in the European Parliament?",
                                        "answer":  "21 representatives"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько представителей имеет Венгрия в Европейском парламенте?",
                                        "answer":  "21 представителем"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Hány tagállama van az Európai Uniónak?",
        "answer":  "27",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "How many member states does the European Union have?",
                                        "answer":  "27"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Сколько государств-членов в Европейском Союзе?",
                                        "answer":  "27"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "number"
    },
    {
        "type":  "Open",
        "question":  "Soroljon fel negy EU-tagállamot!",
        "answer":  "Ausztria ÷ Belgium ÷ Bulgária ÷ Ciprus ÷ Csehország ÷ Dánia ÷ Észtország ÷ Finnország ÷ Franciaország ÷ Görögország ÷ Hollandia ÷ Horvátország ÷ Írország ÷ Lengyelország ÷ Lettország ÷ Litvánia ÷ Luxemburg ÷ Magyarország ÷ Málta ÷ Németország ÷ Olaszország ÷ Portugália ÷ Románia ÷ Spanyolország ÷ Svédország ÷ Szlovákia ÷ Szlovénia",
        "translations":  {
                             "en":  {
                                        "question":  "List ten EU member states!",
                                        "answer":  "Austria ÷ Belgium ÷ Bulgaria ÷ Cyprus ÷ Czech Republic ÷ Denmark ÷ Estonia ÷ Finland ÷ France ÷ Greece ÷ Netherlands ÷ Croatia ÷ Ireland ÷ Poland ÷ Latvia ÷ Lithuania ÷ Luxembourg ÷ Hungary ÷ Malta ÷ Germany ÷ Italy ÷ Portugal ÷ Romania ÷ Spain ÷ Sweden ÷ Slovakia ÷ Slovenia"
                                    },
                             "ru":  {
                                        "question":  "Перечислите десять государств-членов ЕС!",
                                        "answer":  "Австрия ÷ Бельгия ÷ Болгария ÷ Кипр ÷ Чехия ÷ Дания ÷ Эстония ÷ Финляндия ÷ Франция ÷ Греция ÷ Нидерланды ÷ Хорватия ÷ Ирландия ÷ Польша ÷ Латвия ÷ Литва ÷ Люксембург ÷ Венгрия ÷ Мальта ÷ Германия ÷ Италия ÷ Португалия ÷ Румыния ÷ Испания ÷ Швеция ÷ Словакия ÷ Словения"
                                    }
                         },
        "inputType":  "text"
    }
]
